Vijay Ashwath S 🔘 Featured

Software Developer seeking roles in Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, C#, SQL, ASP. Net, LINQ, WEBAPI, ADO. Net, MVC, Angular JS, Web Service, Angular, iQuery, HTML



Current Designation: Software Developer -Dot Net Total Experience: 3 Year(s) 2 Month(s)

Current Company: RANDSTAD INDIA PVT LIMITED Notice Period: 1 Month

Current Location: Chennai Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Chennai

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Application Maintenance, Project Management, Requirement Analysis, Solution Architecture, C#, SQL, ASP. Net, LINQ, WEBAPI, ADO. Net, MVC, Angular

JS, Web Service, Angular, ¡Query, JavaScript, HTML

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Summary

3.4 Years of Experience as Software Developer in Software Design, analysis, development, testing and implementation of web and client server applications using Microsoft Technologies.

Hands on in application development using with C#, Web forms in ASP.NET using C# as the code- behind language And ADO.NET and LINQ as the Database Data consumer.

Extensive Experience in design and development of application using.NET and Web technologies like CSS, Ajax, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, Bootstrap.

Experience in IIS, Ajax, Payment Integration.

Experience in Web Services.

Experience in Windows Services.

Experience in Web API.

Experience in Windows Application.

Experience in Writing Stored procedures using MS SQL Server2008/2012/2014/2017.

Ability to learn & develop using new Technologies quickly.

Work Experience

RANDSTAD INDIA PVT LIMITED as Software Developer -Dot Net

Jan 2020 to Till Date

Project 6: One Randstad - HRMS (app in play store).

Duration: Jul 2020 - Till now.

Client: Randstad India Private Limited.

Role: .NET Developer.

Technical environment: Visual Studio Code, C#, Angular 8, LINQ, SQL Server 2014, Web API, Ionic, Dev Express. Description: This is based on that employee will mark their leave & attendance. It will goes to the corresponding managers. The manager will approve/reject the request from employee.

Responsibilities:

Developed application using C#, Angular 8, Dev Express, Ionic, Web API.?

Design the UI part with bootstrap, jQuery, Html 5 and CSS.?

Involved in creation of stored procedures in MS SQL Server 2014.?

Involved in creation of Web API's and LINQ Queries.?

Worked intensively on business logic and user interface.?

Helping to team and maintain the coding standard and timely delivery of module.?

VINZAS SOFTWARE SOLUTIONS INDIA PVT LIMITED as Software Developer

Sep 2018 to Jan 2020

Project 4: Automated Building Plan Approval Systems (ABPAS). Duration: Oct 2018 - Apr 2019.

Client: Urban Development & Housing Municipality (UDHP), Maharashtra Government.

Role: .NET Developer.

Technical environment: .NET 2017, C#, Angular JS 2.0, LINQ, Web Service, SQL Server 2017, Windows Service.

Description: This is based on that while Constructing New Building the Architect (User) will get approval from government through this application.

Responsibilities:

Developed application using C#, Angular JS.

Design the UI part with bootstrap and jQuery and CSS.

Helping to team and maintain the coding standard and timely delivery of module.

Involved in creation of stored procedures in MS SQL Server 2017.

Involved in creation of triggers in MS SQL Server 2017.

Involved in creation of Web API's and LINQ Queries.

Worked intensively on business logic and user interface.

Involved in creation of Web Services, Windows Services.

Project 5: Building Plan Approval Management System (BPAMS). Duration: May 2019 - Jan 2020.

Client: Town & Country Planning Department (T & CP), Goa Government.

Role: .NET Developer.

Technical environment: .NET 2017, C#, Angular JS 2.0, LINQ, Web Service, SQL Server 2017, Windows Service,

Windows Application.

Description: This is based on that while applicant is going to build a New Construction, he/she will register their corresponding details which is given in the application and will get approval from the corresponding officers. After he/she gets approval from the corresponding officers, the login credential is created to that applicant and he/she will able to submit their building plans that will goes to the corresponding officers, The officers can Approve/Reject their plans, once he/she got approval from all the officers and plan got digitally signed, after he/she will able to build their construction.

Responsibilities:

Developed application using C#, Angular JS.

Design the UI part with bootstrap and jQuery and CSS.

Involved in creation of stored procedures in MS SQL Server 2017.

Involved in creation of Web API's and LINQ Queries.

Worked intensively on business logic and user interface.

Helping to team and maintain the coding standard and timely delivery of module.

Involved in Payment Integration (using Algorithms namely: - CRC32, AES).

Involved in creation of Web Services, Windows Services, and Windows Application.

REBHA TECHNOLOGIES PVT LIMITED as Software Developer

May 2017 to Aug 2018

Project 1: Store Management. Duration: Jun 2017 - Sep 2017.

Client: Planet Pop Corn Foods & Services.

Role: .NET Developer.

Technical environment: .NET 2012, C#, ASP.NET, SQL Server 2008 R2.

Description: It's a Pop Corn Production & Supply application based on the Customer Requirement & Request. It Contains

4 Modules 1. Material Request 2. Production Supply 3. Material Distribution 4. Stock Maintenance

Responsibilities:

Responsible for designing Web forms using different ASP.NET Server controls.

Used ADO.net to connect the database using the SQL Server .NET data provider.

Responsible for testing-unit testing of all modules during any enhancement.

Worked extensively with data bound controls like Grid view.

Used ASP.NET validations control for side validations.

Used java script validation for client-side validations.

Used Regular Expression, Required Field, Range, Compare validation for server-side validations.

Involved in creation of stored procedures in MS SQL Server 2008 R2.

Involved in creation of triggers in MS SQL Server 2008 R2.

Project 2: Telecom Management (SPECTRAFM). Duration: Oct 2017 - Feb 2018.

Client: Adani Groups. Role: .NET Developer.

Technical environment: .NET 2015, C#, ASP.NET, SQL Server 2008 R2.

Description: It's a based on that when User can request Sim, Mobile, Handset etc., through this application and the request will pass to the department and issuing the products based on their request.

Responsible for designing Web forms using different ASP.NET Server controls.

Used ADO.net to connect the database using the SQL Server .NET data provider.

Responsible for testing-unit testing of all modules during any enhancement.

Worked extensively with data bound controls like Grid view.

Used ASP.NET validations control for side validations.

Used java script validation for client-side validations.

Used Regular Expression, Required Field, Range, Compare validation for server-side validations.

Involved in creation of stored procedures in MS SQL Server 2008 R2.

Involved in creation of triggers in MS SQL Server 2008 R2.

Project 3: Club Management. Duration: Mar 2018 - Sep 2018. Client: Rotary 3232(Chennai).

Role: .NET Developer.

Technical environment: .NET 2015, C#, ASP.NET, SQL Server 2008 R2.

Description: This Application based on adding or removing a member to the club & adding events, projects and news by

the (Secretary or President) of the club.

Responsibilities:

Responsible for designing Web forms using different ASP.NET Server controls.

Used ADO.net to connect the database using the SQL Server .NET data provider.

Responsible for testing-unit testing of all modules during any enhancement.

Worked extensively with data bound controls like Grid view.

Used ASP.NET validations control for side validations.

Used java script validation for client-side validations.

Used Regular Expression, Required Field, Range, Compare validation for server-side validations.

Involved in creation of stored procedures in MS SQL Server 2008 R2.

Involved in creation of triggers in MS SQL Server 2008 R2.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Agni College of Technology, Thalambur in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
Windows XP/7/8/8.1/10			
MS OFFICE			
C#, SQL, ASP .Net			
LINQ, WEBAPI, ADO .Net			
Mvc, Angular Js			
Web Service, Windows Service			
Angular 8, Ionic, Dev Express			
HTML, CSS, JQUERY			
JavaScript, Bootstrap			

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Tamil				

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time